let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "Choose the correct option. 'Wetin you say make i tell dem?'",
        answer: "D. What do you want me to say to them?",
        options: [
          "A. Lets find out what you told them.",
          "B. Its a trick. There is no question at all.",
          "C. Ask a person 'What do they think they know?'.",
          "D. What do you want me to say to them?",
          "E. None of the above. A rhetorical question."
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "What does 'commot der' mean?",
        answer: "A. Move over.",
        options: [
            "A. Move over.",
            "B. Move down.",
            "C. Come out here.",
            "D. Stay there."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "which word is appropriate when making a statement of intent(positive or negative) or seeking confirmation?",
        answer: "D. Suppose/No suppose.",
        options: [
            "A. Gree/No gree.",
            "B. Fit/No fit.",
            "C. For say/No for say.",
            "D. Suppose/No suppose."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "An intent (something you want to do). Complete this sentence 'I ____ ____ follow you talk before",
        answer: "A. 'been', 'wan'",
        options: [
            "A. 'been', 'wan'",
            "B. 'for' come",
            "C. 'sha' 'wan'",
            "D. 'suppose', 'fit'"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "Esosa is angry. which of these is a word for angry in pidgin?",
        answer: "B. para.",
        options: [
            "A. Ment.",
            "B. para.",
            "C. shayo.",
            "D. mayan."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "What does it mean to see shege or for a person's eyes to see shege?",
        answer: "A. suffer.",
        options: [
            "A. suffer.",
            "B. Joy.",
            "C. Receive Knowledge.",
            "D. Something Vulgar."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "What is the function of and difference between 'I be' and 'I dey' when used in a sentence?",
        answer: "D. 'I be' is used to ascribe a trait to yourself and 'I dey' refers to a state of being.",
        options: [
            "A. They mean the same thing and can be used interchangeably.",
            "B. 'I be' refers to a current state of being and 'I dey' is used to ascribe a trait to yourself.",
            "C. They mean 'I am' and 'I are' There is no function or difference.",
            "D. 'I be' is used to ascribe a trait to yourself and 'I dey' refers to a state of being."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "Choose the correct meaning of 'Follow me waka'?",
        answer: "C. Walk with me.",
        options: [
            "A. Dance with me.",
            "B. Follow me home.",
            "C. Walk with me.",
            "D. Join me for lunch."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "You want to make it known that your patience is wearing thin, what do you say?",
        answer: "C. I go change am for you o.",
        options: [
            "A. I go tear you slap o.",
            "B. I don strong face.",
            "C. I go change am for you o.",
            "D. Make we yarn commot abeg."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Fill in the gaps for 'She tell me say ____ fine girl, na why ____ happy'",
        answer: "B. 'I be', 'I dey'",
        options: [
            "A. 'I dey', 'I be' ",
            "B. 'I be', 'I dey'",
            "C. 'I be', 'I be'",
            "D. 'I dey', 'I dey'"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "Body dey catch you means?",
        answer: "C. You are excited.",
        options: [
            "A. You seem to have an itch.",
            "B. You are restless.",
            "C. You are excited.",
            "D. You are irritated."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "Who is an 'Amebo (ah-may-boh)?'",
        answer: "D. A gossip.",
        options: [
            "A. A liar.",
            "B. A cheat.",
            "C. A fool.",
            "D. A gossip."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "A person who was coddled, born with a silver spoon and is out of touch is called?",
        answer: "A. Ajebota/botti - (Ajeh-buh-tah).",
        options: [
            "A. Ajebota/botti - (Ajeh-buh-tah).",
            "B. Oga - (uh-gah).",
            "C. Lepa/Orobo - (leh-kpah/uh-ruh-buh).",
            "D. Mugu - (moogoo)."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Which city is the capital of Nigeria?",
        answer: "C. Abuja.",
        options: [
            "A. Port-Harcourt.",
            "B. Benin City.",
            "C. Abuja.",
            "D. Lagos City. "
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "If pesin tell you say e dey catch cruise, wetin e mean?",
        answer: "A. kidding around.",
        options: [
            "A. kidding around.",
            "B. Feeling ill.",
            "C. Restless.",
            "D. excited."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "You see your comrade for outside, how you go hail am normally?",
        answer: "B. How far?",
        options: [
            "A. Guy.",
            "B. How far?",
            "C. shebi?",
            "D. oga.",
            "E. sup?"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "Pidgin is a derivative of the English language hence the name 'Pidgin English'. However, there are words from many nigerian tribes incorporated in it. Select the most popular languages.",
        answer: "E. Yoruba, Hausa, Igbo, Bini.",
        options: [
            "A. Igbo, Itsekiri, Urhobo, Ibibio.",
            "B. Yoruba, Igbo, Hausa, Etsako.",
            "C. Ijaw, Igbo, Esan, Ibibio.",
            "D. Efik, Igbanke, Bini, Rivers.",
            "E. Yoruba, Hausa, Igbo, Bini."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "Nigerian Dishes are some of the most delicious in the world. Say you tried some 'Moi-Moi elewe' and you enjoyed it, Select the correct expression.",
        answer: "B. E too make brain.",
        options: [
            "A. The food na correct shege.",
            "B. E too make brain.",
            "C. Omoh e kasala...no be small o.",
            "D. Yawa don gas for my mouth.",
            "E. Yummy Yummy in my tummy."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "What Situation is 'I for say' typically used?",
        answer: "D. When making a suggestion.",
        options: [
            "A. When correcting someone.",
            "B. Narrating in past tense.",
            "C. Narrating in present tense.",
            "D. When making a suggestion.",
            "E. Getting confirmation."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "To give something away freely to someone is to ____ them and an extravagant display of wealth and opulence is called?'",
        answer: "B. 'Dash', 'Doings'",
        options: [
            "A. 'Deck', 'Opor' ",
            "B. 'Dash', 'Doings'",
            "C. 'Bam', 'Pana'",
            "D. 'Gobe', 'Orisirisi'"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 21,
        question: "You witnessed a person being beaten black and blue... You are disappointed. What is the appropriate expression?",
        answer: "C. Na wah o.",
        options: [
            "A. eeh heeehn naim do esef.",
            "B. hmm.",
            "C. Na wah o.",
            "D. Shioooooooorrrr."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 22,
        question: "You witnessed a person being beaten black and blue...You are glad because they deserved it. What is the appropriate expression?",
        answer:  "A. eeh heeehn. naim do esef.",
        options: [
            "A. eeh heeehn. naim do esef.",
            "B. hmm.",
            "C. Na wah o.",
            "D. Shioooooooorrrr."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 23,
        question: "Select the Meaning of the word 'Trenches'.",
        answer: "E. Substandard living conditions or state of mind.",
        options: [
            "A. Jungle or wild.",
            "B. Adventure.",
            "C. Hard labor.",
            "D. Having to do with tenacity. A state of being.",
            "E. Substandard living conditions or state of mind."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 24,
        question: "Which of these is the correct translation of this question 'you don chop breakfast before?'",
        answer: "C. Ever been broken hearted?",
        options: [
            "A. Have you already eaten?",
            "B. Did you already organize your breakfast?",
            "C. Ever been broken hearted?",
            "D. Have you witnessed disaster before?"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 25,
        question: "'Bros J don Run am for me'. Who is 'Bros J' and what does 'Run am' mean?",
        answer: "D. 'Jesus', 'Do it'",
        options: [
            "A. 'Boss', 'Complete it' ",
            "B. 'All persons with a name starting with  the letter J', 'Buy it'",
            "C. 'My Brother', 'carry it'",
            "D. 'Jesus', 'Do it'"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 26,
        question: "I tell am say 'i go' go but 'i neva' ready. what does 'i go' and 'i neva' mean in this scenario?",
        answer: "B. 'i will', 'i'm not'",
        options: [
            "A. 'have to', 'never' ",
            "B. 'i will', 'i'm not'",
            "C. 'i have', 'cannot'",
            "D. 'i am', 'will never'",
            "E. 'i will', 'never'"
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 27,
        question: "An alternative word for sabi is grab...which is to know, understand or be able to. There is 1 more...What is it?",
        answer: "B. Fit.",
        options: [
            "A. sama.",
            "B. Fit.",
            "C. ehen.",
            "D. Gidigba.",
            "E. take."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 28,
        question: "To fall a persons hand is to what?",
        answer: "A. Disappoint or Embarrass.",
        options: [
            "A. Disappoint or Embarrass.",
            "B. Reject or Rebuke.",
            "C. Deceive or Gaslight.",
            "D. Retaliate or Take revenge."
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 29,
        question: "The saying 'You want to Bam..bah?' originated from a song and in that song 2 nigerian languages were spoken together. What are they?",
        answer: "C. 'Bini', 'Yoruba'",
        options: [
            "A. 'Hausa', 'igbo'",
            "B. 'Youruba', 'Isokoh'",
            "C. 'Bini', 'Yoruba'",
            "D. 'Igbo', 'bini'",
            "E. 'Isoko', 'Hausa'",
         ]
    },
    {
        numb: 30,
        question: "The opposite of being able to do something is what in pidgin? see examples for context.",
        answer:  "B. You no go fit try am.",
        options: [
            "A. Dem no go sabi the road.",
            "B. You no go fit try am.",
            "C. she fit neva get am.",
            "D. Dem nor no weda e carry am."
         ]
    }
    
];